그대를 왕의 핸드로
임명하노라
I would name you
the Hand of the King.
내겐 아들이 있고
네겐 딸이 있지
I have a son, you have a daughter,
we'll join our houses.
가문을 합치는거야
타르가르옌 가문의
비세리스입니다
May I present Viserys
of House Targaryen
그리고 그 여동생
대너리스입니다
and his sister
Daenerys?
난 그 녀석에게 왕비를 주고
그 녀석은 내게 군대를 주는거야
I give him a queen
and he gives me an army.
Maester says the boy may live.
마에스터가 말하길
살지도 모른다더군
사랑하는 동생아, 가끔 네가
어느 편인지 의심될 때가 있구나
My dear brother, there are times you
make me wonder whose side you're on.
내가 얼마나 가족을
사랑하는지 알잖아
You know how much
I love my family.
밤의 경비대에서 복무하는 것은
큰 영광이다
There's great honor serving
in the Night's Watch.
스타크는 수천년 동안
장벽을 지켜왔단다
The Starks have
manned the wall
for thousands of years.
And you are a Stark.
그리고 너도 스타크란다
로버트 왕의 서자들--
King Robert's bastards--
Jon Arryn tracked them all down. Why?
존 아린이 왜
그들을 찾아다닌거요?
왕에게는 적실 아들이 없소
The King has
no trueborn sons.
- 자식들을 사랑하겠지?
- 진정으로 그렇습니다
- Do you love your children?
- With all my heart.
- No more than I love mine.
- And they're all Jaime's.
- 나도 내 자식들을 사랑한다
- 모두 제이미의 자식이기도 하고요
왕이 사냥에서 돌아오면
사실대로 고하겠습니다
When the King returns from
his hunt, I'll tell him the truth.
내 것을 받으러 온거야
I want what I came for. I want
the crown he promised me.
내게 약속했던 왕관을 원해
- No! No!
- A crown for a king.
- 안돼! 안돼!
- 왕을 위한 왕관이다
He was no dragon.
그는 용이 아니었어
용은 불에 죽지 않아
Fire cannot kill the dragon.
존 스노우
Jon Snow,
Lord Commander Mormont
모르몬트 사령관께서
널 직속 집사로 요청하셨다
has requested you
for his personal steward.
널 사령관으로 키울 생각인거야
He wants to groom you
for command.
네드!
Ned! We were hunting.
사냥 중이었어요
로버트가 죽을때면
우리 둘 모두 늦었을거에요
By the time Robert dies, it will be
too late for the both of us.
스타니스는 어쩌고요?
그는 당신의 형입니다
What about Stannis?
He's your older brother.
지금 누가 망할놈의
계승 서열 얘기한답니까?
This isn't about the bloody
line of succession.
그는 왕의 재목이 아니에요
왕은 바로 납니다
He's not a king.
I am.
이제는 새 왕의 시대다
- We have a new king now.
- Your son has no claim to the throne.
당신 아들은 왕좌를
가질 자격이 없소
Kill him! Kill all of them!
I command it!
죽여라!
다 죽여버려!
내 명령이다!
킹스랜딩으로 출두하여
새 왕에게 충성을 맹세하라는 명입니다
You're summoned to King's Landing
to swear fealty to the new king.
내 아버질 잡아가두더니
이젠 뒷구멍을 빨아달라고?
Joffrey puts my father in chains;
now he wants his ass kissed?
그렇다면 킹스랜딩에 가되
홀로 가진 않겠다
I'll go to King's Landing,
but not alone.
기수들을 소집하라
Call the banners.
- 죽여버려
- 살려두는 쪽이 이익이야
- Kill him, Robb.
- He's more use to us alive than dead.
So long as I am your king,
내 치세에서는
반역자가 처벌받지 않는
일은 없을 것이다
treason shall never
go unpunished.
안돼!
- No! No!
- Stop, my son.
멈추거라 아들아
넌 킹스랜딩으로 가서
You will go
to King's Landing
내 대리로서
왕의 핸드가 될 것이다
and serve as Hand
of the King in my stead.
꼬마 왕을, 필요하다면 그 어미도,
통제할 것이다
You'll bring that boy king to heel,
and his mother, too, if needs be.
제발 집으로 보내줘요
Please let me go home.
어머니께서 아직
너랑 결혼하라시니
Mother says I'm still
to marry you,
넌 여기 남아서
복종하는거야
so you'll stay here
and obey.
제 검은 당신의 것입니다
승리하든 패배하든
My sword is yours
in victory and defeat.
북부의 왕!
The King in the North!
북부의 왕!!
니 이름이 뭐라고?
What's your name?
아리
- Arry.
- Arry the orphan boy.
고아 소년 아리
여기서 장벽까진
천릿길이다!
It's 1,000 leagues
from here to the Wall.
내일, 장벽 너머로
출격한다
We ride out
beyond the Wall tomorrow.
밤의 경비대는
무장하고 싸울 것이다
The Night's Watch
will ride in force
그것이 야인이건
백행귀건
against the wildlings,
the White Walkers,
무엇이건 간에 말이다
and whatever else
is out there.
오늘 밤이면 죽을겁니다, 칼리시
He will die tonight, Khaleesi.
밤의 땅에선 용의 알이
필요한 일은 없을겁니다
Drogo will have no use for
dragon eggs in the Night Lands.
당신은 몰라요
You don't understand.
내 혈족이시여
Blood of my blood.
디씨 기미갤
구름과땅
2012/4/2 오후 1:30분
♪ Game of Thrones 2x01 ♪
The North Remembers
Original Air Date on April 1, 2012
피드백은 디씨 기미갤
불펌은 하든지 말든지
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
왕좌의 게임 S02E01
북부는 기억한다
좋은 공격이군
Well struck.
좋은 공격이었다, 개야
Well struck, Dog.
Did you like that?
좋았어?
좋은 공격이었습니다
전하
It was well struck,
Your Grace.
그건 내가 했던말이고
I already said
it was well struck.
예, 전하
Yes, Your Grace.
다음은 누구지?
- Who's next?
- Lothor Brune,
로소르 브룬!
베일리쉬 경을 섬기는
자유기수입니다!
freerider in the service
of Lord Baelish.
상대는 홀라드 가문의
'붉은 서 돈토스'
Ser Dontos the Red
of House Hollard.
홀라드 가문의
붉은 서 돈토스!
Ser Dontos the Red
of House Hollard!
나 왔어요
Here I am.
나 왔어
죄송합니다, 전하
Sorry, Your Grace.
심히 송구합니다
My deepest apologies.
- Are you drunk?
- No.
취했나?
아닙니다
아니,
아 실은 전하...
Uh, no.
No, Your Grace.
포도주 두 잔을 마셨습니다
- I had two cups of wine.
- Two cups?
두 잔?
That's not much at all.
별로 마시지도 않았군
Please,
have another cup.
한잔 더 마시게나
진심이십니까, 전하?
Are you sure, Your Grace?
물론이지, 내 명명일을
기념하는 의미에서 마시게
Yes. To celebrate
my name day.
두번 마시게
마시고 싶은 만큼 마셔
Have two.
Have as much as you like.
I would be honored,
Your Grace.
영광입니다, 전하
서 메린, 서 돈토스의
기념을 좀 도와주겠나?
Ser Meryn, help Ser Dontos
celebrate my name day.
See that he drinks
his fill.
배가 터질 때까지
마시게 하라고
You can't.
안돼요!
뭐라고?
What did you say?
방금 나보고
안된다고 그랬나?
Did you say I can't?
전 그냥...
I only meant
it would be bad luck
불길한 일이라고요
명명일에
사람을 죽이시면요
to kill a man
on your name day.
무슨 농부들이나 믿을법한
미신인건지...
What kind of stupid
peasant's superstition...
The girl is right.
아이 말이 옳습니다
명명일에 심은대로
What a man sows
on his name day
일년 내내 거둔다고들 하지요
he reaps all year.
Take him away.
끌어내라
이 어릿광대 같은 놈은
내일 죽여야겠다
I'll have him killed
tomorrow, the fool.
He is.
맞아요
어릿광대--
정말 현명하셔요
A fool--
you're so clever to see it.
He'll make a much better fool
than a knight.
기사보단 광대에
어울리는 놈이에요
깨끗한 죽음 같은 자비를
받을 자격이 없어요
He doesn't deserve
the mercy of a quick death.
아가씨 말씀 들었나,
서 돈토스?
Did you hear My Lady,
Ser Dontos?
오늘부터 넌
내 광대다
From this day,
you'll be my new fool.
감사합니다, 전하
Thank you, Your Grace.
그리고 아가씨도요,
감사합니다
And you, My Lady,
thank you.
사랑하는 조카야!
Beloved nephew.
전장에서 널 찾아다녔지 뭐니
We looked for you
on the battlefield.
어디에도 없더구나
You were nowhere
to be found.
여기 있었는데요,
왕국을 다스리면서
I've been here,
ruling the kingdoms.
얼마나 훌륭히 다스리셨던지
What a fine job
you've done.
Look at you.
오 세상에
훨씬 아름다워졌구나
More beautiful
than ever.
그리고 너!
너는 아...
And you! You-- you're going to be
bigger than the hound,
조금만 있으면 사냥개보다
커지겠구나
얼굴도 사냥개보다 잘 생겼고
but much better looking.
이 친구는 날 안좋아하지
This one doesn't like me.
당최 이유를 모르겠네요
Can't imagine why.
죽었다고 들었는데요
- We heard you were dead.
- I'm glad you're not dead.
삼촌이 죽지 않아서 기뻐요
나도 그렇단다
Me, too, dear.
죽음은 참 지루한 일이거든
Death is so boring,
especially now
특히 지금처럼 세상이
재밌게 돌아갈땐 말이야
with so much excitement
in the world.
아가씨, 삼가 조의를 표합니다
My Lady, I'm sorry
for your loss.
Her loss?
조의?
얘 아버지는
반역자였는데!
Her father was
a confessed traitor.
그래도 아버지는 아버지지
But still her father.
특히 너처럼 근래들어 아버지를
잃은 처지면 공감할법도 한데말야
Surely having so recently
lost your own beloved father
you can sympathize.
제 아버지는 반역자였어요
My father was a traitor.
제 어머니와 오빠도 반역자에요
My mother and brother
are traitors, too.
I am loyal
to my beloved Joffrey.
전 사랑하는 조프리에게
충성을 다하고 있어요
물론 그러시겠지
Of course you are.
뭐 그럼, 명명일을 즐기시지요
전하
Well, enjoy your name day,
Your Grace.
Wish I could stay
and celebrate,
저도 남아서 축하하고 싶습니다만
해야할 일이 있어서 말이죠
but there is work
to be done.
무슨 일?
What work?
왜 여기 온건데요?
Why are you here?
아성(Citadel)에서 보낸 까마귀가
오늘 아침에 도착했습니다, 전하
The raven arrived
from the Citadel
- this morning, Your Grace.
대의회가 열려,
The conclave has met,
considered reports
칠왕국 전역의 마에스터들이
보낸 조사 결과를 검토했습니다
from Maesters all over
the Seven Kingdoms,
and declared
this great summer
그리고 발표하길...
이 대 여름이 끝이 났다고 합니다
done at last.
근래 들어 가장 긴 여름이었지요
The longest summer
in living memory.
농부들은 긴 여름 뒤엔
더 긴 겨울이 온다고 믿지요
The peasants say,
a long summer means
- an even longer winter.
- A common superstition.
흔한 미신이지요
We have enough wheat
for a five-year winter.
5년은 버틸 밀이 저장되어 있습니다
겨울이 그보다 더 오래간다면...
If it lasts any longer,
...농부들 수가 좀 줄겠지요
we'll have
fewer peasants.
The city's drowning in refugees,
Your Grace, fleeing the war.
도시에 전쟁 난민들이
넘쳐납니다, 전하
We have nowhere
to house them.
지금도 수용하기 힘든데
겨울이 오면 사태는
더 심각해질겁니다
And with winter coming,
it'll only get worse.
당신은 시 경비대를 지휘하지,
그렇지 않은가, 슬린트 경?
You command the City Watch,
do you not, Lord Slynt?
그러합니다, 전하
I do, Your Grace.
그리고 내 휘하의
영주이기도 하겠지?
And are you not
a Lord at my command?
제 작위와 영지는 모두
전하께서 자비로이 내려주신겁니다
I owe my title and lands
to your generosity, Your Grace.
그럼 자네 할 일을 하게
농부들이 도시에 들어오지 못하게 막아
Then do your job.
Shut the gates to the peasants.
그들이 있어야 할 곳은 논두렁이지
우리의 수도가 아니야
They belong in the field,
not our capital.
알겠습니다, 전하
Yes, Your Grace.
Don't get up.
일어날 필요는 없습니다
그 어느때보다 아름답구나, 누나
More ravishing than ever,
big sister.
전쟁이 체질에 맞나봐?
War agrees with you.
방해해서 죄송합니다, 계속 하세요
Forgive the interruption.
Carry on.
여기서 뭘 하는거지?
What are you doing here?
아, 정말 비범한
여행이었지
Ah, it's been
a remarkable journey.
장벽 너머에 오줌을 쌌고
I pissed off the edge
of the Wall,
하늘 감옥에서 자보기도 하고
I slept in a sky cell,
산악 부족들과 함께
싸우기도 했지
I fought with
the hill tribes--
수많은 모험을 겪었고,
so many adventures,
감사해야 할 일도 많지
so much to be
thankful for.
여기서 뭘 하고 있냐고?
이곳은 소회의장이야
What are you doing here?
This is the small council.
맞아, 내 생각에
왕의 핸드는
Yes. Well I, do believe,
the Hand of the King,
모든 소회의에서 환영일 것 같은데
is welcome at all
small council meetings.
왕의 핸드는 우리 아버지야
Our father
is Hand of the King.
그래, 하지만 아버지의
부재중엔...
Yes, but in his absence...
춘부장께서 전쟁에
나가 계시는 동안
Your father has named
Lord Tyrion
to serve as Hand
in his stead while he fights.
티리온 경을 왕의 핸드로
임명하셨습니다
나가! 모두 나가!
Out! All of you out!
네가 어떻게 아버질 속여서
이 일을 하게 만들었는지 궁금하군
I would like to know
how you tricked father into this.
내가 아버질 속일 정도의
사람이었다면
If I were capable
of tricking father,
I'd be emperor
of the world by now.
지금쯤은 전세계의 황제가 됬겠지
누나가 자초한거야
You brought this
on yourself.
난 아무것도 안했어
I've done nothing.
맞아
아무것도 안했지
Quite right--
you did nothing
누나 아들이 네드 스타크의
머리를 날려버리는 동안 말이야
when your son called
for Ned Stark's head.
이제 북부 전체가 봉기했어
Now the entire North
has risen up against us.
- I tried to stop it.
- Did you? You failed.
- 멈추려고 했어
- 그래? 그럼 실패했군
그 촌극의 결과가 우리 가문을
족히 한 세대는 따라다닐거야
That bit of theater will haunt
our family for a generation.
롭 스타크는 아이일 뿐이야
- Robb Stark is a child.
- Who's won every battle he's fought.
여태껏 싸운 모든 전투를
이긴 아이지
우리가 전쟁에
지고 있다는건 알겠지?
Do you understand
we're losing the war?
- What do you know about warfare?
- Nothing.
니가 전쟁에 대해 뭘 안다고?
아무것도 모르지
하지만 난 사람에 대해선
좀 알아
But I know people.
우리 적들이 우릴
증오하는 것 만큼이나
And I know that our enemies hate
each other
자기네들끼리도 증오한다는 것은
알지
almost as much
as they hate us.
조프리는 왕이야
- Joffrey is King.
조프리가 왕이지
넌 왕에게 조언을 하러 온거고
You are here
to advise him.
난 왕에게 조언하러 왔지
I'm only here
to advise him.
왕이 내 말을 잘 듣는다면
And if the King listens
to what I say,
어쩌면 제이미 삼촌을
돌려 받을지도 모르는 일이지
the King might just get
his Uncle Jaime back.
어떻게?
How?
누나는 자식들을 사랑하지?
You love your children.
누나의 몇 안되는
장점이지
It's your one
redeeming quality.
그 광대뼈랑 함께 말이야
That and your cheekbones.
스타크도 자식 사랑이 극진하지
The Starks love
their children as well.
우리는 그 자식을
둘이나 잡아놓고 있고
- And we have two of them.
- One.
하나야
하나라고?
- One?
- Arya, little animal-- she disappeared.
아리아, 그 작은 짐승이
사라졌어
사라졌다고?
뭐 바람과 함께 사라지셨나?
Disappeared?
What, in a puff of smoke?
교환할 스타크가 셋이나 있었는데
We had three Starks
to trade.
하나는 머리를 날려버리고
하나는 도망가게해?
You chopped one's head off
and let another escape.
아버지께서 진노하시겠군
Father will be furious.
묘한 기분이겠어
It must be odd for you...
실망스런 자식 역할을 맡다니
to be the disappointing child.
옛 신들께서 도련님의 형과
북부의 아들들을 굽어살피시길...
My Lord, may the Old Gods
watch over your brother
and all our northern sons.
제 성벽은 겨울을 넘기지
못할겁니다
The walls of my holdfast
will not stand the winter.
마지막으로 회반죽을 바른게
아에리스 왕 시절이었습니다
The stones were last mortared
in the time of King Aerys,
그리고 요즘은
석공들도 예전만 못합니다
and I'm afraid
the masons today
are not fit to carry
their fathers' hammers.
제 어린 시절에는
When I was a boy,
I remember seeing them
토렌 광장에 새 탑을 쌓아올리는데
여름 한철밖에 걸리지 않았지요
put up a new tower
at Torrhen's Square in a summer.
그때 사람들은
일이란걸 할 줄 알았습니다
Men worked back then.
오늘날엔, 제 성은 마치
Today, my holdfast
looks like it was built
술 취한 어린애들이
쌓아놓은 것 같습니다
by drunk children.
밤에는 벽의 틈으로
바람이 숭숭새는 소리가 들리지요
At night you can hear the wind
howling through the gaps.
And the Gods
forbid it rains.
그리고 비라도 내리면
오 신들이시여
Why, I might as well sleep
beneath a waterfall.
폭포 밑에서 자는거랑
다를게 없습니다
성의 관리는
Maintenance of a holdfast
generally falls
to the lord of that holdfast.
대개 그 성의 영주가
맡습니다만
대개는 그렇지
Generally, yes,
but I've sent
all the young men off
하지만 난 롭 스타크의 전쟁에
젊은이들을 모조리 보냈다고
to fight
Robb Stark's war.
'롭 왕'이겠지
그리고 '롭의 전쟁'도 아니야
King Robb.
And it's not his war.
원해서 하는 것이 아니니까
He didn't choose it.
그럴지도 모르지요 도련님
Maybe not, My Lord,
하지만 기수를 불러서 병사들을
끌고 간 것도 사실 아닙니까?
but he called in his banners
and took the men.
조프리가 내 아버지를 죽였어
Joffrey killed my father,
당신의 주군 말이야
your liege lord.
서약은 기억하고 있겠지?
Do you remember
your vows, Ser?
물론 기억하고 있습니다!
Of course I remember!
We can spare four masons
for a week, My Lord.
석공 넷을 일주일 동안
빌려드릴 수 있습니다, 영주님
성벽을 수리하는데
그 정도면 되겠지요?
Will that be sufficient
to repair your walls?
그..그 정도면 될 것 같소
I-- I believe it will.
하루 종일 읍소하게
내버려둘 순 없었잖니?
We didn't want him here
all day, did we?
롭 얘기하는 말투가
맘에 안들었어
I didn't like the way
he was talking about Robb.
나도란다
Nor did I.
하지만 듣고 싶지 않은 사람들
말을 듣는것도
But listening to people
you'd rather not listen to
윈터펠의 영주로서의 책임이란다
is one of your responsibilities
as Lord of Winterfell.
포탄 경
Lord Portan.
옛 신들께서 도련님의 형과
북부의 아들들을 굽어살피시길...
My Lord, may the Old Gods
watch over your brother
and all our northern sons.
한 시간 동안 끓이고
그 물을 마시면
Boil this for an hour
and drink the tea.
모든 고통이
사라지지
Makes all your pain
go away.
난 아무데도 안 아픈데
Don't have any pain.
좋겠네
Lucky for you.
저기로
That way.
또 그 꿈을 꾸고 있구나
You've been having
those dreams again.
꿈 안 꿔
I don't dream.
꿈 안 꾸는 사람은 없어
Everyone dreams.
난 안 꿔
I don't.
혜성 얘기하는거
들었어
Heard some of the men
talking about the comet.
예언이래
They say it's an omen.
롭이 남부에서 큰 승리를
거둘거라는 징조래
They say it means Robb will win
a great victory in the South.
그래?
Did they?
어떤 멍청이들은
저게 라니스터의 붉은색이라던데
I heard some other fools
say it's Lannister red.
라니스터가 얼마 안있어
온 칠왕국을 다스린다는 의미라면서
Means the Lannisters will rule
all Seven Kingdoms before long.
말구종 하나는 저게
피라고도 하고
Heard a stableboy say
it's the color of blood
네 아버지의 죽음을
기리기 위한거라며
to mark the death
of your father.
별이 사람을 위해
떨어지는 일은 없어
The stars
don't fall for men.
붉은 혜성이 뜻하는건
딱 하나야, 꼬마야
The red comet means
one thing, boy--
용
dragons.
용은 모두 죽었어
The dragons are all dead.
몇 세기 전에 모두
They've been dead
for centuries.
Mmm.
Mmm. Mmm.
오빠께서 뭐라도 말해준게
없었나요, 칼리시님?
What did your brother say
about them, Khaleesi?
고기를 먹는댔어
He said they ate meat.
어떤 종류의 고기인지는
말 안했던가요?
He didn't tell you
what kind of meat?
내 오빠는 용에 대해
아는게 없었어
My brother didn't know
anything about dragons.
뭐든간에 아는 것은 하나도 없었지
He didn't know anything
about anything.
Eh.
드로고의 첫 선물이었어
She was Drogo's
first gift to me.
기억합니다
I remember.
보호해주겠다고 약속했어
I promised
to protect them.
그들의 적들은 모두 비명을
지르며 죽게 할거라고도 약속했고
Promised them their enemies
would die screaming.
무슨 수로 굶주림을
비명지르게 만들지?
How do I make
starvation scream?
저도 아는 바가 없습니다
A trick I never learned,
I'm afraid.
이 사막에
끝이 있긴 한거야?
Does it ever end?
저도 동쪽으로 이렇게
멀리 가본적은 없습니다
This is farther east
than I've ever been.
하지만 끝이 있는건
분명합니다
But, yes, Khaleesi,
모든 것에는 끝이 있습니다
설령 붉은 사막이래도요
everything ends,
even the Red Waste.
And you're sure
there's no other way?
다른 길이 없는건
정말 확실한거고?
남쪽으로 가서
라자린의 땅에 들어간다면
If we go south to the land
of the Lazarheen,
'양치기족'들이 우릴 죽이고
용을 뺏아갈겁니다
the Lamb Men will kill us
and take your dragons.
서쪽으로 가서
'도트락 해'로 들어간다면
If we go west
to the Dothraki Sea,
처음 마주치는
칼라사르가
the first
Khalasar we meet
우릴 죽이고
용을 뺏아가겠지요
will kill us
and take your dragons.
누구도 내 용을
뺏을 순 없어
No one will take
my dragons.
아직 싸우기엔 너무 약합니다
They are too weak to fight,
우리 사람들도 그렇고요
as are your people.
전하께서 그들의
힘이 되어야합니다
You must be
their strength.
당신이 내 힘이듯이...
As you are mine.
라카로, 아고, 코바로
남은 말들을 모두 끌고가라
너는 동쪽으로
너는 남동쪽으로
넌 북동쪽으로 가라
무엇을 찾으면 됩니까, 칼리시?
도시, 사람이 살건 폐허건
상단과 사람들
강과 호수, 혹은 염해
이 붉은 사막이 어디까지
펼쳐졌는지
그 너머에 무엇이 있는지
라카로
Rakharo...
네가 나의 마지막 희망이다
혈족이여
절대 실망시키지 않겠습니다
내 혈족이여
한번도 실망시킨적 없어
You never have.
시작하기엔 안 좋은 때네요
This is bad time to start.
일이 잘 안풀려?
Having a rough time of it?
아직 죽지는 않았는걸 뭐
Nothing's killed me yet.
대신 니 궁둥짝이
썰매를 죽였지
- Your ass killed the sledge.
- You offered me a ride.
타라고 한건 너였잖아?
물집 갖고 징징대는거
듣기 싫어서 그랬다 왜?
I just wanted you to shut up about
your damn blisters.
내가 태어난 곳이 딱 이랬지
I was born in a place
like this.
그때가 좋은 시절이었어
Later, I fell
on hard times.
저거 여자야?
Are those girls?
크래스터의 딸래미들이지
Craster's daughters.
여자 못본지 여섯 달이었어
I haven't seen a girl
in six months.
나라면 그냥 계속
못보고 말겠어
I'd keep on not seeing them
if I were you.
What, he don't like people messing
with his daughters?
크래스터가 딸 집적거리는거
싫어하나보죠?
자기 부인 집적거리는거
싫어하는거지
He don't like people
messing with his wives.
자기 딸들이랑
결혼하거든
He marries
his daughters,
딸한테서 딸을 낳고
and they give him
more daughters.
계속 돌고 도는거지
And on and on it goes.
그게 뭐야 씨발
- That's foul.
- It's beyond foul.
진짜 씨발이네
이 근방 백 리그 안의
야인들은 모두 사라졌지
All the other wildlings for a
hundred leagues have disappeared.
근데도 크래스터는 남았고
Craster's still here.
뭔가 꿍꿍이가 있겠지
He must be doing
something right.
아들들은 어떻게 되지?
What happens
to the boys?
음?
- Hmm?
- He marries his daughters.
딸들이랑 결혼하면
아들들은 어떻게 하냐고
What does he do
with his sons?
프로스트팽으로 가는 길에
He said he planned
to stop here
이곳에 들를 계획이라고
말했소
on his way
to the Frostfangs.
다들 계획이야 새우지
People make
all sorts of plans.
3년 동안 벤젠 스타크를 못 봤어
I haven't seen Benjen Stark
in three years.
그립지도 않더군
Haven't missed him.
언제나 날 쓰레기 취급했거든
Always treated me
like scum.
맛 좋은 포도주 마셔본지가
한 세월이지
Haven't had any good wine
for a long time.
너희 남부인들이 포도주 하나는
잘 만든다니까, 그거 하난 인정해
You Southerners make good wine,
I'll give you that.
우린 남부인이 아닙니다
We're not Southerners.
이 계집애는 누구야?
Who's this little girl?
내 딸년들 절반보다 예쁘구만
You're prettier
than half my daughters.
다리 사이에 촉촉한
구멍이라도 있으신가?
You got a nice wet twat
between your legs?
이름이 뭐냐?
What's your name?
존 스노우
- Jon Snow.
- Snow, eh?
스노우라 그거지?
내 말 똑바로 듣거라
사생아야
Listen to me, bastard.
장벽 남쪽에서 올라온 놈들은
다 남부인인거야
All you lot from south of the Wall,
you're Southerners.
지금 와서야 북부에 도착한거지
진짜 북부 말이야
But now you're in the North,
the real North.
무슨 뜻이 있어서
말한건 아닐게요
The lad meant no harm.
만약 저 기생오래비처럼 생긴
사생아놈이 내 딸이랑...
I catch that pretty little bastard
talking to my daughters--
아무도 당신 딸들이랑
얘기 하지 않을거요, 약속하겠소
No one will talk to your daughters,
you have my word.
이제 앉아서
입 닥치고 있거라
Now, sit down
and shut your mouth.
맛 좋은 포도주 좀
가져왔나?
You bring any of that
good wine with you?
그렇소
We did.
이곳에 오는 동안
여섯 개의 마을을 지났소
We passed through
six villages on the way here.
모두 텅 비어 있었지
All six were abandoned.
이 야인들이 전부
어디로 갔단 말이오?
Where have all
the wildlings gone?
말해줄 수도 있지만,
목이 좀 마르군
I could tell you,
but I'm thirsty.
There's a barrel of
Dornish wine on the sledge.
썰매에 도른 포도주 통이 있다
가져오거라
- Bring it in here.
- Yes, commander.
알겠습니다
다들 어디로 갔는지
알고싶나?
You want to know
where they've all gone?
북쪽으로...
North... to join up
with Mance Rayder...
만스 레이더와 합류하러 갔지
니 오랜 친구 말야
Your old friend.
그는 내 친구가 아니오
He's no friend of mine.
그는 서약을 깨고
형제들을 배신했소
He broke his vows,
betrayed his brothers.
아 그래
Oh, aye.
한때는 가난한 까마귀였다가
But once he was
just a poor black crow.
'장벽 너머의 왕'이 되셨지
And now he's
King-Beyond-the-Wall.
몇년째 스스로를 그렇게
부르고 있소만
He's been calling
himself that for years.
그가 도대체 무엇의 왕이란 말이오?
꽝꽝 얼어붙은 호수짝?
What's he king of?
A frozen lake somewhere?
썩 괜찮아 보이는 도끼군
That's a good-looking axe.
갓 만들어졌나?
Fresh forged?
이리 주거라
Give it here.
흑성(Castle Black)에서
하나 더 만들어주마
You'll have another one
made at Castle Black.
여기 있소
Here.
아, 정말 사랑스러운 강철이군...
Oh, that's some
lovely steel.
만스 레이더가 뭘 하고 있는지
알고싶나?
You want to know
what Mance Rayder is doing?
군대를 소집하는거지
Gathering an army.
내가 듣기론 이미
What I hear,
he's already got more men
너희 남부 왕들도 뛰어넘는
숫자를 모았다더군
than any of your
southern kings.
이 군대를 어디로
이끌 계획인거요?
And where does he plan
marching this army?
저 북쪽 끝에서 출발하면
When you're
all the way north,
한 방향 말고 갈 곳이
있겠나?
there's only
one direction to go.
야생에서 혼자 살기엔
좋지 않은 시기요
These are bad times to be
living alone in the wild.
매서운 바람이
불고 있소
The cold winds
are rising.
마음대로 불라지
내 뿌리는 깊으니까
Let them come.
My roots are sunk deep.
여편네야
Wife...
까마귀 경한테 우리가
얼마나 잘 지내는지 말씀드려라
tell the Lord Crow
how content we are.
이곳이 우리가 살 곳이에요
This is our place.
우리 남편이 안전하게 지켜줘요
Our husband keeps us safe.
노예로 죽느니
자유롭게 사는게 나아요
Better to live free
than die a slave.
부럽지 않나, 노인 양반?
Don't it make you
jealous, old man,
난 이렇게 영계들 끼고 사는데
to see me with
all these young wives
넌 침대를 뎁혀줄
계집 하나 없고?
and you with no one
to warm your bed?
다른 길을 선택한 것 뿐이오
We chose different paths.
그래, 소년들 밖에 없는
길을 택한거지
Oh, aye, and you chose the path
with no one but boys on it.
내 지붕 밑에서 자고 싶겠지?
You'll be wanting to sleep
beneath my roof, I suppose,
내 돼지들도 축내고?
and eat me out of pigs.
지붕은 환영이오
A roof would be welcome.
힘든 여정이었소
It's been hard riding.
식량은 우리 스스로 가져왔소
당신을 위해 좋은 무기도 갖고왔고
We've brought our own food
and good steel for you.
누구든 내 부인들에게
손 댔다간
Any man lays a hand
on one of my wives,
손 날아갈 줄 알아라
he loses the hand.
누구든 빤히 쳐다보면
And I see this one
staring too long,
눈을 뽑아내버릴 수도 있다
I might just gouge
his eyes out.
당신의 집에선
당신 뜻대로지요
Your roof, your rules.
내가 누구냐?
Who am I?!
내가 누구냐고?
- Who am I?!
- Lord Commander.
사령관이요
넌 뭐냐?
- And who are you?
- Jon Snow.
존 스노우요
넌 뭐냐니까?
Who are you?
집사입니다
Your steward.
언젠가 사람들을
지휘하고 싶으냐?
You want to lead
one day?
그럼 지휘 받는 법부터
배워라
Then learn
how to follow.
빛의 군주시여, 어둠 속에 갇힌
우리에게 임하소서
Lord of Light, come to us
in our darkness.
이 거짓 신들을
당신에게 바치나이다
We offer you
these false Gods.
이를 받으시고
당신의 빛을 우리에게 비춰주소서
Take them and cast
your light upon us...
밤은 검고 공포로 가득합니다
For the night is dark
and full of terrors.
밤은 검고 공포로 가득합니다
For the night is dark
and full of terrors.
긴 여름이 끝나고,
After the long summer,
짙은 암흑이 온 세상에
드리우리라
darkness will fall heavy
on the world.
별들은 피를 흘리고
The stars will bleed.
막아야 합니다
We need to stop her.
겨울의 차가운 숨결이
바다를 얼릴지니...
The cold breath of winter
will freeze the seas...
지금은 안되오
Not now.
북방에서 망자가 되살아나리라
...And the dead shall rise
in the North.
당신들은 모두 일곱 신의
축복하에 명명된 자들이오!
All you men were named
in the Light of the Seven!
우리 아버지의 신들을 이렇게
다루는 것이 가당키나하오?
Is this how you treat
the Gods of your fathers?
그렇게도 조상들의 얼굴에
침을 뱉고 싶소?
Are you so eager to spit
on your ancestors?
당신에게서 공포의
냄새가 나는구나
You smell of fear--
공포와 오줌, 그리고
늙은 뼈...
fear and piss
and old bones.
날 멈추고 싶나?
Do you want to stop me?
멈춰봐
Stop me.
고대의 기록에서 전하길,
In the ancient books,
it's written
한 전사가 불길 속에서
타오르는 검을 뽑으리니
that a warrior will draw
a burning sword from the fire.
그 검이 바로
'빛의 인도자'이다
And that sword shall be
Lightbringer.
스타니스 바라테온
Stannis Baratheon,
빛의 전사여,
warrior of light,
당신의 검이 기다리고 있습니다
your sword awaits you.
주여, 당신의 빛을
우리에게 비춰 주소서!
Lord, cast your
light upon us!
밤은 검고 공포로 가득합니다
For the night is dark
and full of terrors.
밤은 검고 공포로 가득하다
For the night is dark
and full of terror.
이 여자는 전하를 이길 가망이
없는 전쟁으로 끌어가고 있소
This woman will lead him
into a war he cannot win.
스타니스는 우리의 왕입니다
Stannis is our king.
우린 그가 이끄는 대로
갈 뿐입니다
We follow
where he leads,
원치 않는 길이라 할지라도요
- even if we don't like the path.
- King.
왕...
그 멧돼지가
로버트를 죽인 후로
Since that boar
killed his brother,
사방 천지에서
칭왕을 하고 있소
every lord wants
a coronation.
난 그자들을 섬기는게 아닙니다
스타니스를 섬기지요
I don't serve the others.
I serve Stannis.
나도 마찬가지요
As do I,
but loyal service
허나 진정한 충성엔 가혹한
진실을 얘기하는 것도 있소
means telling
hard truths.
그의 주변엔 광대와
광신자뿐이오
He's surrounded
by fools and fanatics,
전하께선 당신을 믿잖소, 다보스
but he trusts you, Davos.
만약 당신이 전하께
진실을 고한다면...
If you tell him
the truth...
무슨 진실 말이오?
What's the truth?
"그리하여 나는 내 가문의
명예에 걸고 선언컨대
"And I declare upon
the honor of my house
나의 친애하는 형제
로버트는...
that my beloved
brother Robert--"
그는 내 '친애하는'
형제가 아니었다
He wasn't
my beloved brother.
난 그를 사랑하지 않았고
그도 나를 사랑하지 않았지
I didn't love him.
He didn't love me.
무해한 수준의 격식입니다, 전하
A harmless courtesy,
Your Grace.
거짓말이다
빼거라
A lie.
Take it out.
"나의 형제 로버트는
적자를 남기지 못했다.
"...that my brother Robert
left no trueborn heirs,
조프리, 토멘, 미르셀라는
사생아로, 근친상간 관계였던
the boy Joffrey,
the boy Tommen,
and the girl Myrcella
being born of incest
세르세이 라니스터와
제이미 라니스터의 자식이다
between Cersei Lannister and
her brother Jaime Lannister.
나의 생득권...
- By right of birth--"
- Jaime Lannister, the Kingslayer.
'국왕살해자' 제이미 라니스터
그대로 부를 것이다
Call him what he is.
...와 국왕살해자 제이미
라니스터의 자식이다
"...And her brother
Jaime Lannister,
the Kingslayer.
나의 생득권과 혈통에 근거하여,
오늘부로...
By right of birth and blood,
I do this day lay claim--"
국왕살해자 서 제이미 라니스터로 정정하라
Make it Ser Jaime Lannister,
the Kingslayer.
무엇이 어찌 되었건간에
그는 기사다
Whatever else he is,
the man's still a knight.
'...와 국왕살해자 서 제이미
라니스터의 자식이다
"Ser Jaime Lannister,
the Kingslayer.
나의 생득권과 혈통에 근거하여
By right of birth
and blood,
오늘부로 칠왕국의 철왕좌에
대한 권리를 주장한다
I do this day lay claim
to the Iron Throne of Westeros.
모든 진실된 자는
충성을 선언하라."
Let all true men
declare their loyalty."
에다드 스타크가 진실을 알았을때,
그는 오직 내게만 알렸다
When Eddard Stark learned
the truth, he told only me.
그와 같은 실수를
하지는 않겠다
I'll not make
the same mistake.
그 편지의 사본을
온 왕국으로 발송하라
Send copies of that letter
to every corner of the Realm,
아보르에서 장벽까지
from the Arbor
to the Wall.
선택의 시간이 왔다
The time has come
to choose.
그 누구도 무지를
핑계삼지 못하리라
Let no man claim ignorance
as an excuse.
전하, 진정한 적은
라니스터입니다
Your Grace, the Lannisters
are the true enemy.
만약, 당분간만이라도 렌리와
화친을 한다면...
If, for the time being, you could
make peace with your brother--
렌리가 칭왕을 계속하는 동안은
화친하지 않을 것이다
I'll not make peace with Renly
while he calls himself King.
이미 많은 사람들이
렌리의 밑으로 들어갔습니다
Well, many have already
declared for him--
메이스 티렐,
랜딜 탈리
Mace Tyrell,
Randyll Tarly.
전하께선 이 영주 저 영주에게
지원을 간청할 필요가 없습니다
Stannis does not need to beg
this lord or that lord for support.
빛의 군주께서
전하를 도우십니다
The Lord of Light
stands behind him.
And how many ships has
the Lord of Light got in his fleet?
빛의 군주께선
배가 몇척이시랍니까?
배가 필요 없으십니다
- He has no need for ships.
- I'm sure he doesn't,
물론 그렇겠지요
전쟁을 할거라면 우리에겐
배가 필요합니다
but we do if we're
going to war.
렌리가 정 안되겠으면, 전하,
롭 스타크와 힘을 합치십시오
If not Renly, Your Grace,
join forces with Robb Stark.
내 왕국의 북쪽 반을
훔치려는 도둑과 말이냐?
Who would steal
the northern half of my kingdom.
난 언제나 도둑들에게
공정한 처벌을 내렸지
I've always served thieves
according to their desserts,
as you well know,
Ser Davos.
자네도 잘 알다시피 말이다,
서 다보스
조프리, 렌리, 롭 스타크
이들은 모두 도둑이다
Joffrey, Renly, Robb Stark,
they're all thieves.
그들이 무릎 꿇지 않으면
내가 모두 꺾을 것이다
They'll bend the knee
or I'll destroy them.
지난번의 불찰을
사과드립니다, 전하
I owe you
an apology, my King.
제 일은 섬기는 것이지요
My duty is to serve.
전하께선 새로운 신을 선택하셨습니다
You have chosen the new God
over the Old Gods.
빛의 군주께서 우리
모두를 굽어 살피시길
May the Lord of Light
watch over us all.
모두 한 잔 하는게 어떻습니까?
Shall we drink together?
하지 마시오
Don't.
단 하나의 진정한 신을
기리기 위한 한 잔 말이오
A cup of wine to honor
the one true God.
밤은 검고 공포로 가득하다
The night is dark and full
of terrors, old man,
하지만 불길이 그 모두를
태워 없앨 수 있지
but the fire
burns them all away.
전하
Your Grace.
북부의 왕!
King in the North.
날 어디 성에라도
가둘 줄 알았는데
I keep expecting you
to leave me
in one castle or another
for safekeeping,
대신 이 야영지에서
저 야영지로 계속 끌고 다니는군
but you drag me along
from camp to camp.
내가 좋아졌냐, 스타크?
Have you grown
fond of me, Stark?
그런건가?
Is that it?
그러고보면 여자랑
같이 있는걸 본 적이 없군
I've never seen you
with a girl.
만약 내가 널 내 기수
중 하나에게 넘긴다면
If I left you with
one of my bannermen,
얼마 지나지 않아
네 아버지가 알게 되겠지
your father would know
within a fortnight
그러면 내 기수는
서신을 하나 받게 될거야
and my bannerman would receive
a raven with a message:
"내 아들을 석방하면 꿈도
꾸지 못했을 부를 주겠다.
"Release my son and you'll be rich
beyond your dreams.
거부하면 네 가문을
완전히 멸족시키겠다."
Refuse and your house
will be destroyed, root and stem."
널 위해 전장에 나서는 사람들의
충성심을 믿지 못한다는 건가?
You don't trust
the loyalty
of the men following
you into battle?
내 목숨을 맡길만큼 믿지
Oh, I trust them
with my life,
네 목숨을 맡길 만큼은 아냐
just not with yours.
영리한 꼬마군
Smart boy.
뭐야?
What's wrong?
꼬마 소리 듣는게
싫은가?
Don't like
being called "boy"?
모욕당했쪙!인가?
Insulted?
누워서 침을 뱉는구나,
국왕살해자
You insult yourself,
Kingslayer.
꼬마에게 패배 당하고
You've been defeated by a boy.
꼬마에게 포로로 잡혀 있고
You're held captive
by a boy.
어쩌면 꼬마 손에 죽을지도 모르지
Perhaps you'll be
killed by a boy.
스타니스 바라테온이
Stannis Baratheon
sent ravens
웨스테로스 전역의
영주들에게 서신을 보냈더군
to all the high lords
of Westeros.
조프리 바라테온 왕은
진정한 왕도 아닐 뿐더러
King Joffrey Baratheon
is neither a true king
진정한 바라테온도 아니라지
nor a true Baratheon.
그는 네 서자야
He's your bastard son.
만약 그게 사실이면
스타니스가 적법한 왕이겠지
If that's true,
Stannis is the rightful king.
얼마나 편해?
How convenient for him.
내 아버지가 진실을
알아냈겠지
My father learned
the truth.
그래서 처형한거고
That's why
you had him executed.
네드 스타크 목이 잘렸을때
난 니 포로였어
I was your prisoner
when Ned Stark lost his head.
네 아들이 죽인거야
Your son killed him
세상이 자기 아버지를
알지 못하게 만드려고
so the world wouldn't
learn who fathered him.
그리고 너--너는 내
동생을 창문에서 밀었지
And you-- you pushed
my brother from a window
네가 왕비와 함께 있는 것을
봤기 때문에
because he saw you
with the queen.
증거는 있나?
You have proof?
아니면 여편네들 하듯이
가십거리라도 교환하잔건가?
Or do you want to trade gossip
like a couple of fishwives?
네 사촌 중 하나를 내 협상 조건과
함께 킹스랜딩으로 보낼거다
I'm sending one of your cousins
down to King's Landing
with my peace terms.
내 아버지가 너랑 협상할거라
생각하나?
You think my father's going
to negotiate with you?
아직 그분을 잘 모르는군
You don't know him
very well.
아니, 그가 곧
나를 알게되겠지
No, but he's starting
to know me.
세번 이겼다고
정복자가 되는건 아냐
Three victories
don't make you a conqueror.
세번 지는 것보단
낫겠지
It's better than
three defeats.
도시가 냄새가 지독해요
This city stinks...
시체 같아요
Like dead bodies.
맞는 말이야
A bit corpsey, yes.
똥 냄새도요
And shit.
여기 오고 싶어하는줄
알았는데?
I thought you wanted
to come here.
정말 좋아요
I love it.
시체랑 똥 냄새가
정말 좋다고?
You love the smell
of dead bodies and shit?
정액이랑 마늘이랑
술도요
And cum and garlic
and rum.
거기서 정액 냄새가
맡아진다고?
You can smell cum
from the balcony?
악취가 좋아요
소음이 좋고
I love the stink.
I love the noise.
도시에 오면
섹스가 하고 싶어져요
Cities make me
want to fuck.
교외에서도 그랬잖아
And so did the country.
이곳이 내가 있을 곳이에요
This is where I belong.
그래, 음, 너
조심해야해
Yes, well, you need
to be careful.
아무도 네가 여기 있는걸
알아선 안돼
No one can know
you're here.
아무도 모를거에요
No one will know.
킹스랜딩에선 누구도
믿어선 안돼
You can't trust anyone
in King's Landing.
거짓말쟁이 천지거든
솜씨 좋은 거짓말쟁이 나쁜 거짓말쟁이
They're all liars--
good liars, bad liars,
위대한 거짓말쟁이도
한둘쯤 있지
one or two great liars.
당신은 뭔데요?
What about you?
나? 난 이곳 출신이 아니야
난 진실의 노예지
Me? I'm not from here.
I'm a slave to the truth.
진실요?
Truth?
당신은 내가 태어나서 본
최고의 쬐끄만 거짓말쟁이에요
You are the biggest
little liar I have ever met.
내가 왜 작다고 생각해?
Why do you think
I am so little?
그 진실들이 날 깔아뭉개고
있어서 내가 이렇게 작은거야
I'm being crushed beneath the
weight of all that truth.
Oh!
네드 스타크가
이곳에서 잤지
Ned Stark actually
slept on this.
불쌍하게도 말이야
As if the poor man
didn't suffer enough.
우리 둘이 이 장소에
신선한 변화를 줘야해
One of the many changes
we'll have to make around here.
베일리쉬 경
- Lord Baelish.
- Your Grace.
전하
부탁 하나 해도 될지
모르겠군
I wonder if I might
ask you for a favor.
말씀만 하십시오, 전하
Of course,
Your Grace.
네드 스타크의 막내 딸
아리아
Ned Stark's youngest
daughter Arya--
찾을 수 없는 것 같군
we can't seem
to locate her.
수도를 탈출했다면
If she's escaped
the capital,
논리적으로 생각해봤을 때
윈터펠로 가야 맞지요
Winterfell seems
the logical destination.
그런데도 북부의 내 친구들은
그녀를 봤다는 보고가 없는데
And yet my friends in the North
report no sign of her.
흥미롭군요
Curious.
만약 스타크와 협상할
일이 생긴다면
If we choose to negotiate
with the Starks,
가치 있는 인질이 되겠지
누구든 그녀를 찾아낸다면--
the girl has some value.
Whoever finds her--
너도 라니스터와 빚에 대한
속담은 들어봤겠지?
well, you know what they say about
Lannisters and debts.
으음, 바리스에게
물어보실 수도 있습니다만
Well, you could ask
Varys where she is.
언제나 답을 내놓는 친구죠
He'll have
an answer for you.
그걸 또 믿는 것은
다른 문젭니다만...
Whether you believe it...
저 본인은 고자들 말을
믿기가 심히 어렵더군요
Myself, I have always had
a hard time trusting eunuchs.
그들이 뭘 원하는지
어떻게 안답니까?
Who knows what they want?
흉내지빠귀
A mockingbird.
스스로 만든 상징이지?
You created your
own sigil, didn't you?
그렇습니다
Yes.
적절하군...
자수성가해서
Appropriate...
for a self-made man
숱한 이야기를
후대에 남길 사람에겐..
with so many
songs to sing.
마음에 드셨다니 다행이군요
I'm glad you like it.
유복한 가문에서 태어나는
행운을 타고난 사람들도 있죠
Some people are
fortunate enough
to be born into
the right family.
나머지는 자기 살 길을
스스로 찾아야만 합니다
Others have to find
their own way.
이야기를 들었지
I heard a song once
아주 유력한 가문에 들어가게 된
한 가난한 소년에 대한 것이었지
about a boy
of modest means
who found his way into the
home of a very prominent family.
소년은 그 집의 맏딸을
사랑했지
He loved
the eldest daughter.
슬프게도, 그녀는
다른 남자를 바라보고 있었어
Sadly, she had eyes
for another.
남녀가 한 집에 살면
When boys and girls
live in the same home,
묘한 상황이 나올 때도 있지요
awkward situations
can arise.
심지어 남매간에도 모종의
애정이 싹트는 경우가 있다 들었습니다
Sometimes, I've heard,
even brothers and sisters
develop
certain affections.
그리고 이 애정이
세상에 알려지면
And when these affections
become common knowledge,
으으음...그거야말로
진정 묘한 상황이겠지요
well, that is an awkward
situation indeed,
특히 그것이 유력한
가문 내의 일이라면 말입니다
especially
in a prominent family.
종종 유력한 가문들은
간단한 진실을 잊곤 하더군요
But prominent families
often forget a simple truth,
전 그 진실을 깨달았습니다
I've found.
무슨 진실이지?
And which truth is that?
아는 것이 힘이라는거지요
Knowledge is power.
붙잡아라
Seize him.
목을 베어라
Cut his throat.
잠깐, 멈추어라
Stop. Wait.
마음이 바뀌었다.
놓아주거라
I've changed my mind.
Let him go.
세 걸음 물러나라
Step back three paces.
몸을 돌려라
Turn around.
눈을 감아라
Close your eyes.
권력이 힘이다
Power is power.
허구헌날 동전이나 세고
갈보들 관리만 하지 말고
Do see if you can
take some time away from
잠시 여유를 내서 스타크 꼬마를
찾아보거라
your coins and your whores
to locate
the Stark girl for me.
그리하면 매우 감사하겠구나
I would very much
appreciate it.
네가 서 알튼 라니스터인가?
You're Ser Alton Lannister?
그렇습니다, 전하
I am, Your Grace.
만약 내 조건을 받아들인다면
네 사촌들에게 평화를 주겠다
I offer your cousins peace
if they meet my terms.
첫째로, 너희 가문은
내 여동생들을 풀어줘야한다
First, your family
must release my sisters.
두번째로, 내 아버지의
유골을 반환하여
Second, my father's bones
must be returned to us
윈터펠 지하의 납골당에서
so he may rest beside
his brother and sister
형제 자매와 함께
영면할 수 있게 해야한다
in the crypts
beneath Winterfell.
내 아버지를 섬기다 죽은
이들의 유골도 모두
And the remains of all those
who died in his service
반환해야한다
must also be returned.
유족들이 적합한 절차를
거쳐 그들을 기릴 수 있도록
Their families can honor
them with proper funerals.
명예로운 요구십니다, 전하
- An honorable request, Your Grace.
- Third...
셋째...
조프리와 섭정대비는
Joffrey and the Queen Regent
must renounce all claim
북부에 대한 모든 권리를
포기해야한다
to dominion of the North.
지금부터 영원히
From this time
till the end of time,
우리는 자유로운 독립국이다
we are a free
and independent kingdom.
북부의 왕...
The King in the North.
북부의 왕!
King in the North.
조프리도, 그의 부하 중 누구도
Neither Joffrey
nor any of his men
우리 땅에 발 끝 하나
들이밀지 못한다
shall set foot
in our lands again.
이 명을 어길시
If he disregards
this command,
내 아버지와 같은 운명을
맞게될 것이다
he shall suffer
the same fate as my father,
단 하나 다른 것은, 난
사형 집행인 따위는 두지 않는다
only I don't need a servant
to do my beheading for me.
이것은, 전하...이것은...
These are-- Your Grace,
these are--
이것이 내 조건이다
These are my terms.
만약 섭정대비와 그 아들이
받아들인다면, 그들에게 평화를 주겠다
If the Queen Regent and her son
meet them, I'll give them peace.
그리하지 않는다면...
If not...
남부를 라니스터의 시체로
뒤덮어 놓겠다
I will litter the south
with Lannister dead.
조프리 왕은 바라테온입니다,
전하
King Joffrey is a Baratheon,
Your Grace.
아 그러냐?
Oh, is he?
너는 날이 밝자마자 출발할
것이다, 서 알튼
You'll ride at daybreak,
Ser Alton.
오늘은 여기서 마치겠다
That will be all
for tonight.
한 말씀 드려도 되겠습니까, 전하?
A word, Your Grace?
아무도 없을땐 "전하"라고
부를 필요 없어
You don't have to call me
"Your Grace" when no one's around.
한번 익숙해지면 그리
나쁘지도 않더라고
It's not so bad
once you get used to it.
너 하나라도 익숙해졌다니
다행이군
I'm glad someone's
gotten used to it.
라니스터는 네 조건을 거부할거야,
알고있지?
The Lannisters are going to reject
your terms, you know?
당연히 그렇겠지
Of course they are.
네가 원한다면 전장에서
싸우는 것도 계속 할 수 있지만
We can fight them
in the fields as long as you like,
킹스랜딩을 함락할때까진
이긴게 아니야
but we won't beat them until you
take King's Landing.
해군 없이 킹스랜딩을
함락할 순 없지
And we can't take
King's Landing without ships.
내 아버지에겐 해군과
숙련된 선원들이 있어
My father has ships and men
who know how to sail them.
내 아버지에게
맞서 싸웠던 선원들 말이지
Men who fought
my father.
남부의 억압에서 벗어나기 위해
싸웠던 사람들이야, 지금 너랑 똑같이
Men who fought King Robert
to free themselves
from the yoke of the South,
just like you're doing now.
난 아버지에게 딱 하나
남은 아들이야
I'm his only living son.
내가 말하면 들어주실거야
분명해
He'll listen to me.
I know he will.
난 스타크가 아니야
나도 그건 알고 있어
I'm not a Stark.
I know that.
하지만 네 아버지가 날
명예를 아는 사람으로 키워냈어
But your father raised me
to be an honorable man.
함께 복수하는거야
We can avenge him
together.
발론 그레이조이와 동맹을
맺는 것은 현명하지 못하단다
You don't want
Balon Greyjoy for an ally.
그의 해군이 필요해요
200척에 달한다는군요
I need his ships.
They say he has 200.
킹스랜딩의 하수구엔
백만마리의 쥐가 산다고 하지!
They say a million rats
live in the sewers of King's Landing.
그 쥐들과도 동맹을 맺을거니?
Shall we rally them
to fight for us?
그레이조이 경을 믿지
못하시는군요
I understand you don't
trust Lord Greyjoy.
내가 그레이조이 경을 믿지 않는건
그가 믿을 수 없는 인물이기 때문이야!
I don't trust Lord Greyjoy because
he is not trustworthy.
그의 반란을 진압하기 위해
네 아버지가 전쟁에 나갔었단다
Your father had to go to war
to end his rebellion.
그래요, 그리고 이번엔
제가 반란자죠
Yes. And now I'm the one
rebelling against the throne.
이전에는 아버지도 반역자였어요
Before me, it was father.
어머니는 반역자와 결혼해서
반역자를 낳은거죠
You married one rebel
and mothered another.
넌 단순한 반역자가 아니란다
I mothered more than
just rebels,
그걸 잊고 있는 것 같구나
a fact you seem
to have forgotten.
만약 국왕살해자를
여자애 둘과 거래했다간
If I trade the Kingslayer
for two girls,
내 기수들이 날 거꾸로
메달아버릴거에요
my bannermen will string me up
by my feet.
그럼 넌 산사를 왕비의
손아귀속에 냅두겠단거니?
You want to leave Sansa
in the Queen's hands?
아리아도!
And Arya--
아리아에 대해선
소식조차 듣지 못했어
I haven't heard
a word about Arya.
그 아이들을 위해서가 아니라면
우린 뭣 때문에 싸우고 있는거니?
What are we fighting for
if not for them?
그렇게 단순한 문제가
아니에요!
It's more complicated
than that!
엄마도 잘 알고 있잖아요!
You know it is.
집으로 가봐야겠구나
It's time for me
to go home.
브랜이랑 릭콘을 못 본지
몇달이 되가는구나
I haven't seen Bran
or Rickon in months.
윈터펠에는 못 가요
You can't go
to Winterfell.
뭐라고?
I beg your pardon?
동생들을 돌보는건 로드릭에게
맡길거에요
I'll send Rodrik
to watch over the boys
엄마는 내일 당장 스톰랜드로 가세요
because tomorrow
you'll ride south to the Stormlands.
도대체 무슨--
Why in the name
of all the Gods--
렌리 바라테온과 협상하는데
필요하기 때문이에요
Because I need you to negotiate
with Renly Baratheon.
렌리는 10만의 군세를
소집했어요
He's rallied
an army of 100,000.
엄마는 그를 알고
그의 가족을 알아요
You know him.
You know his family.
난 렌리 바라테온이 꼬마이던 시절
후로는 본 적도 없어!
I haven't seen Renly Baratheon
since he was a boy.
보낼만한 다른 영주도
수십 수백이--
You have a hundred
other lords--
이 영주들 중에서 누가 더
엄마보다 믿을만 한데요?
Which of these lords
do I trust more than you?
만약 렌리가 우리 편을 든다면
If Renly sides with us,
우리 숫자는 적의 두배가 되요
we'll outnumber them
two to one.
그렇게까지 몰리면, 저쪽에서
협상을 걸어올거에요
When they feel the jaws beginning
to shut, they'll sue for peace.
그리고 동생들을 돌려 받는거죠
We'll get the girls back.
그때 집으로
돌아가면 되는거에요
Then we'll all
go home... for good.
동이 틀때 떠나마
I will ride at first light.
모두 다시 모일 수 있을거에요
약속해요
We will all be together
again soon, I promise.
정말 잘해줬단다
You've done so well.
네 아버지도 아주..
자랑스러워 할거야
Your father
would be... proud.
- 렌리 경에게 안부 전해줘요
- 렌리 왕이지
- Give Lord Renly my regards.
- King Renly.
이제 사방 천지에 왕이구나
There's a king
in every corner now.
이게 뭐지?
What is all this?
이 방을 적합한 외양으로
돌려놓는거죠
Returning this room
to its proper appearance.
타르가르옌에 대해 뭐라고 하든
어쨌든 그들은 정복자였어요
Say what you will about the Targaryens--
they were conquerors.
저것은 정복자의 왕좌구요
That is a seat
for a conqueror.
거기에 어울리는 방이 필요해요
포도 덩굴이니 꽃이니 하는 것들 말고
It needs a room to match it,
not vines and flowers.
아리아 스타크를 찾지 못했단다
We can't find Arya Stark.
운 좋으면 어딘가에
죽어 나자빠져 있겠죠
With luck, she's dead
in a ditch somewhere.
어쩌면 그렇지. 만약 아니면
우린 그녀가 필요해
Perhaps. But if not,
we need her.
산사 하나로는 절대
제이미를 돌려주지 않을거야
They'll never give Jaime back
to us for Sansa alone.
돌려줄지도 모르죠.
놈들은 약해빠졌어요
I think they might.
They're weak.
여자에 너무 높은
가치를 둔다니까요
They put too much value
on their women.
아리아를 찾을 병력을
내보내야해
We need to set our armies
to the task of finding her.
동원할 수 있는 최대한의
인원을
Send out as many men
as we can.
만약 네가 할아버지에게
부탁한다면...
I'm sure if you asked
grandfather--
왕은 부탁하지 않아요.
명령하지
The King does not ask;
he commands.
그리고 할아버지의 멍청이짓이
And my grandfather's
stupidity in the field of battle
삼촌을 잡히게 한 이유라고요
is the reason Robb Stark has
Uncle Jaime in the first place.
네 삼촌의 목숨이
걸려있어
His life is in danger.
우린 전쟁 중이에요
We're at war.
우리 모두의 목숨이 걸려있죠
All our lives
are in danger.
삼촌에 관한 역겨운
거짓말을 들었어요
I heard a disgusting lie
about Uncle Jaime.
삼촌이랑 엄마요
And you.
적들은 무슨 말이든지 할거란다
Our enemies
will say anything
왕좌에 대한 네 주장을
약화시키기 위해서라면
to weaken your claim
to the throne.
주장이 아니라
왕좌는 내꺼에요
It's not a claim.
The throne is mine.
물론 그렇지
Of course it is.
누구도 그런 흉한
거짓말은 믿지 않는단다
No one believes
this foul gossip.
누군가는 믿겠죠
Someone believes it.
아버지에게
다른 아이들이 있었다고요?
Father had
other children?
저랑 토멘이랑 미르셀라
말고요?
Besides me and Tommen
and Myrcella?
뭘 묻고 있는거니?
What are you asking?
엄마에게 지쳤을때
다른 여자랑 잤던건지 묻는거에요
I'm asking if he fucked
other women
when he grew tired
of you.
도대체 얼마나 많은
사생아--
How many bastards
does he have running--
방금 엄마가 한거
사형에 처할 수도 있어요
What you just did
is punishable by death.
다신 그런 짓
하지 마세요
You will never
do it again.
다시는
Never.
이만 가볼게요
That will be all,
Mother.
아냐, 아냐, 아냐, 아냐
No, no, no, no.
너 네가 내는 소리가
얼마나 우스운지는 알고 있니?
Do you have any idea
how ridiculous you sound?
빠져들란 말이야
Ease into it.
천천히, 열정을 담아서
Slowly, with passion.
Oh, yeah.
가서 씻고 옷 입어
Go wash yourselves.
Put some clothes on.
둘 다 오늘밤부터
일 할거야
Both of you
are working tonight.
이곳은 좀 달라, 데이지
We do things
differently here, Daisy.
여긴 헤이시드 홀에서
동전 다섯개 내고 노는 곳이 아니라고
This isn't some five-copper
bawdy house in Hayseed Hall.
- 헤이스택 홀이요
- 뭐든간에
- Haystack Hall.
- Wherever you're from.
우리 업소는
Our establishment
doesn't cater
농부랑 양치기 같은건 안 받아
to ploughmen
and goat herders.
올센 경
Lord Olsen.
이곳에선 취향이
모든걸 결정하지
Taste is
everything here.
리틀핑거는 참
대단한 것 같아요
Littlefinger's
a fancy man.
리틀핑거라고 부르지마
Don't call him
Littlefinger.
안 좋아해
He doesn't like it.
베일리쉬 경이라고 해야지
Lord Baelish.
공용어를 못하는 것처럼
군다니까
She pretends she doesn't
speak the common tongue
이국적인 척하는거지
so that people
will think she's exotic.
실은 바로 아래의 벼룩 골목에서
태어났지
She grew up just down the road
in flea bottom.
아름다워요
She's beautiful.
그냥 멍청한 걸레야,
뭐 근데 인기는 많지
She's a dumb slut, really,
but a lid for every pot.
사령관님
Lord Commander.
다시 만나서...정말
반가워요
Good to see you...
again.
이 업소가 페티르 바엘리시 경
You do realize
this establishment
is owned by
Lord Petyr Baelish,
왕의 재무장관 소유인건
아시죠?
the King's
Master of Coin...
많은 사람들 주머니에
들어가는 돈을 관리하시는...
Coin which goes
in many pockets.
- 명령이다
- 누구 명령이요?
- Orders.
- Whose orders?
리틀핑거 따위 신경쓰지
않는 사람
Someone who doesn't care
what Littlefinger thinks.
안돼, 안돼요!
제발!
No, you can't.
No! Please!
안돼! 바라!
No! Not my Barra!
- 제발, 제발...
- 됐다, 처리해
- Please. Please.
- Enough. Get it done.
죽여버려
- Kill the bastard.
- No, no!
- 제발...
- 이리 내놔
- Please.
- Give it here.
안돼, 제발...
No, please.
산개해라, 모든 집을 수색해!
Spread out.
Search every house.
방들 다 뒤져! 모두!
Every room.
Look in every room.
People shouting )
겐드리!
이름이 겐드리였어요!
Gendry!
His name is Gendry.
그 사생아놈 어딨어?
Where is
the bastard?
밤의 경비대요!
제발 그만!
The Night's Watch!
Please, stop!
어디?
Where?
왕의 대로로 데려갔어요,
북쪽으로요
They took him up the Kingsroad,
heading north.
- 어떻게 알아보지?
- 황소 머리 투구를 가졌어요!
- How will we know him?
- He's got a bull's head helmet.
- 직접 만든거에요
- 찾아내
- He made it himself.
- Find him.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==